Alexander Shved

An intelligent and ambitious person. An experienced web developer focused on delivering high quality code up to the highest personal standard. A consistent, semantic, responsive and cross-platform code is natural to my development cycle. My front end expertise will be a valuable asset to any team dedicated to producing the best possible browsing experience.

26 Clyde Road, Knowle, Bristol, BS4 3DH

07871792047 a.shved90@gmail.com http://shved.uk/

EXPERIENCE

Fresh8Gaming, Bristol — Web engineer

November 2017 - PRESENT

Started working with a wide range of technologies from Goland and PostgreSQL to Vue.js and basic markup and styling to bring client widgets to life. Over the course of the role helped plan and build dynamic tools to minimize dev time and shorten widget creation from 1 month to 1 week using a combination of Vue and bash scripts.

Element78, Bristol — *Middleweight web developer*

March 2016 - June 2017

I worked closely with Frontend and Backend teams to evaluate and improve current development cycle, research and present new technologies to the office to further optimize the development process and bring both teams closer together for a tighter collaboration and seamless integration of their work.

Deep Blue Sky, Bath spa — Front end web developer

July 2015 - March 2016

Amazing place to work at, utmost attention to detail, great relationship with clients, full support from back end developers and always great care to deliver a website that everyone in the office can be proud to put their name on.

EDUCATION

Gloucestershire University, Cheltenham — Degree

September 2009 - May 2013

Modules Included Linux and Cisco networking, Website development, Database design, Java development.

Dissertation Topic of choice: How current Web Technologies allow SMEs to compete with larger competitors in the context of mobile content delivery and service provision

SKILLS

Semantic HTML/HAML

BEM-based CSS/LESS/SASS

Mobile first & Cross-browser

WAI & a11y accessible

ES5-6 JS

Great with Vue

Basics in React

Basics in .NET, PHP and SQL

Experience with WP/Umbraco

LANGUAGES

English

Latvian

Russian